Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
[Fated Hearts]
[قلوب مصيرية]
[Episode 13]
[الحلقة 13]
Have a taste, Your Highness.
تفضل بالتذوق، سموكم.
I made them myself.
لقد صنعتهم بنفسي.
I'm not fond of sweets.
أنا لا أحب الحلويات.
My bad.
خطئي.
I should've asked first.
كان ينبغي لي أن أسأل أولا.
Today, Father set our wedding
اليوم، حدد الأب موعد زفافنا
for ten days from now.
لمدة عشرة أيام من الآن.
I have a gift for you.
عندي لك هدية.
This is the only thing
هذا هو الشيء الوحيد
my birth mother left me.
لقد تركتني والدتي الحقيقية.
My brother said
قال أخي
it counts
إنه مهم
as her dowry for me.
كمهرها لي.
We'll each keep one piece.
كل واحد منا سوف يحتفظ بقطعة واحدة.
May it carry her blessing
فليحمل لها البركة
from above
من الأعلى
to keep you safe and well all your life.
للحفاظ على سلامتك وصحتك طوال حياتك.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Besides this,
وبالإضافة إلى ذلك،
there's another thing
هناك شيء آخر
I need to explain to you.
أريد أن أشرح لك.
This time,
هذه المرة،
my brother
أخي
made you stay in Susha,
جعلك تبقى في سوشا،
but it wasn't my wish.
ولكن لم تكن هذه رغبتي.
After the wedding,
بعد الزفاف،
I'll do everything I can
سأفعل كل ما بوسعي
to persuade Father to let us leave.
لإقناع الأب بالسماح لنا بالمغادرة.
Please don't hold it
من فضلك لا تمسكها
against me
ضدي
or grow suspicious because of it.
أو يثير الشكوك بسبب ذلك.
You're overthinking.
أنت تفكر كثيرًا.
Am I really?
هل انا حقا؟
I can see whether you're
أستطيع أن أرى ما إذا كنت
upset or pleased.
منزعج أو مسرور.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
I'll always
انا سأفعل دائما
stay by your side
ابقى بجانبك
and serve you as your wife
وأخدمك كزوجتك
and your right hand.
ويدك اليمنى.
Whether our two countries are at war or peace,
سواء كانت بلدينا في حالة حرب أو سلام،
in good times or bad,
في الأوقات الجيدة أو السيئة،
I'll never break
لن انكسر ابدا
the promise I've made today.
الوعد الذي قطعته اليوم.
You're so kind to me.
أنت لطيف معي جدًا.
I've no way to repay it.
ليس لدي طريقة لسدادها.
Hearing you say that
سماعك تقول ذلك
puts my mind at ease.
يطمئنني.
It's getting late.
لقد أصبح الوقت متأخرًا.
You'd better head back.
من الأفضل أن تعود.
Advisor Xiao has been captured by Feng Suige.
تم القبض على المستشار شياو من قبل فينج سويجي.
Have you told His Highness?
هل أخبرت سموه؟
Let me see him at once.
دعني أراه في الحال.
[Jingming Garden]
[حديقة جينغمينغ]
I have urgent news to report.
لدي أخبار عاجلة أريد أن أبلغكم بها.
Officer Ning.
الضابط نينغ.
His Highness already knows.
سموه يعلم ذلك بالفعل.
He asked me to tell you
لقد طلب مني أن أخبرك
that everything
أن كل شيء
must wait until after the wedding.
يجب الانتظار حتى بعد الزفاف.
There were Jinxiu's undercover guards lying in wait on the way.
وكان حراس جينكسيو المتخفون ينتظرون في الطريق.
And they knew
وعرفوا
they couldn't make a move in Yujing City,
لم يتمكنوا من التحرك في مدينة يوجينج،
so they used those children
لذلك استخدموا هؤلاء الأطفال
to force her out.
لإجبارها على الخروج.
As for who has the power
أما من لديه القوة
to command those undercover guards,
لقيادة هؤلاء الحراس السريين،
you don't need me
أنت لا تحتاجني
to tell you, do you?
لأخبرك، هل تفعل؟
[Pub]
[حانة]
What?
ماذا؟
Thinking of putting an arrow
أفكر في وضع سهم
straight through Xia Jingshi's heart?
مباشرة من خلال قلب شيا جينغشي؟
Seems the famed Jinxiu general's thirst
يبدو أن عطش الجنرال جينكسيو الشهير
for vengeance is no lie.
لأن الانتقام ليس كذبة.
You captured Xiao Weiran
لقد قمت بإلقاء القبض على شياو ويران
and told Ning Fei everything.
وأخبرت نينغ في بكل شيء.
It's even worse than killing them.
إنه أسوأ من قتلهم.
How vicious.
كم هي شريرة.
The bond between the Three Heroes of Jinxiu
الرابطة بين أبطال جينكسيو الثلاثة
has become a toy in your hands.
أصبحت لعبة في يديك.
If I didn't do this, how else could I get the truth?
إذا لم أفعل هذا فكيف يمكنني أن أحصل على الحقيقة؟
If you've got a better way,
إذا كان لديك طريقة أفضل،
I'll hear it.
سأسمعها.
Let go.
اتركه.
I said let go!
قلت دعها تذهب!
Why do something that grieves those close to you
لماذا تفعل شيئا يحزن المقربين منك
and pleases your enemies?
ويرضي أعدائك؟
My affairs are none of your concern.
شؤوني لا تعنيك.
I'll make them my concern.
سأجعلهم مصدر قلقي.
Let go!
اتركه!
♪ The rain drifts endlessly ♪
♪ المطر ينهمر بلا نهاية ♪
♪ The old dream burns the heart ♪
♪ الحلم القديم يحرق القلب ♪
Ever since I fell off that cliff,
منذ أن سقطت من ذلك المنحدر،
♪ Dreams sink into ruin ♪
♪ الأحلام تغرق في الخراب ♪
I've lived for only two things:
لقد عشت من أجل أمرين فقط:
to find out who wants to kill me
لمعرفة من يريد قتلي
♪ Missing the warmth of your palm ♪
♪ أفتقد دفء راحة يدك ♪
and why.
ولماذا.
I joined hands with you
لقد انضممت إليك
♪ Awaiting dusk ♪
♪ في انتظار الغسق ♪
only for the sake of revenge.
فقط من أجل الانتقام.
♪ Shadows take root in the mountain pass ♪
♪ الظلال تتجذر في ممر الجبل ♪
Now there's one question left:
الآن بقي سؤال واحد:
why does Xia Jingshi want me dead?
لماذا يريد شيا جينغشي موتي؟
♪ In just a moment, tears stained ♪
♪ في لحظة واحدة، تلطخت الدموع ♪
Once I've fulfilled my promise
بمجرد أن أفي بوعدي
to you,
لك،
we'll be even.
سوف نكون متساويين.
I understand how you're feeling right now.
أنا أفهم كيف تشعر الآن.
Being abandoned by everyone close to you
التخلي عنك من قبل كل من هو قريب منك
is truly painful.
إنه مؤلم حقا.
♪ Love is a trial, harsh and cold ♪
♪الحب هو اختبار قاسي وبارد ♪
♪ Who crushes the lingering pain for me? ♪
♪ من يسحق الألم المتبقي بالنسبة لي؟ ♪
Those who haven't truly lived it
أولئك الذين لم يعيشوها حقًا
will never understand.
لن أفهم أبدًا.
♪ Clouds vanish, rain ceases, seek me ♪
♪تختفي السحب، يتوقف المطر، ابحث عني ♪
Don't speak of it so lightly.
لا تتحدث عن هذا الأمر باستخفاف.
Do you know why
هل تعلم لماذا
my father and I
أنا وأبي
grew distant?
أصبحت بعيدة؟
Years ago, my mother was murdered,
منذ سنوات، قُتلت والدتي،
and he turned a blind eye.
وأغض الطرف.
Not only did he get himself a new empress,
ولم يحصل على إمبراطورة جديدة فحسب،
but he also forbade anyone
ولكنه نهى أيضا عن ذلك
from mentioning my mother again.
من ذكر والدتي مرة أخرى.
He even forced me to call the culprit Mother.
حتى أنه أجبرني على مناداة الجاني بـ "الأم".
And the old nursemaid
والمربية العجوز
who'd been with me since I was born—
الذي كان معي منذ ولادتي
to win favor with my enemy,
لكسب رضا عدوي،
she tried
لقد حاولت
to burn me alive in my sleep.
ليحرقني حيًا أثناء نومي.
And my swordsmanship teacher…
ومعلمي في المبارزة...
They all used my trust
لقد استخدموا جميعهم ثقتي
and tried every possible way
وحاولت كل الطرق الممكنة
to kill me.
لقتلي.
I suppose this is what they call
أعتقد أن هذا ما يسمونه
being betrayed by everyone.
تعرضت للخيانة من قبل الجميع.
Unfortunately, I was hard to kill
لسوء الحظ، كان من الصعب قتلي
and survived.
ونجا.
The powerful First Prince of Susha—
الأمير الأول القوي لسوشا—
exalted
مرتفع
and ruthless—
وقاسية-
yet not at all
ولكن ليس على الإطلاق
the glorious figure
الشكل المجيد
others imagine.
كما يتخيله الآخرون.
That's why staying alive
لهذا السبب البقاء على قيد الحياة
is what matters most.
هو ما يهم أكثر.
Why are you telling me this?
لماذا تقول لي هذا؟
Maybe…
ربما…
because we share the same misery.
لأننا نتقاسم نفس البؤس.
Give me your hand.
أعطني يدك.
♪ Take down the setting sun as my heart ♪
♪أنزل غروب الشمس على قلبي ♪
♪ Fold the heaven and earth to make my wings ♪
♪ أطوي السماء والأرض لأصنع أجنحتي ♪
♪ If fate shows no mercy ♪
♪ إذا لم يظهر القدر أي رحمة ♪
♪ Then don't blame my recklessness ♪
♪ إذن لا تلوموني على تهوركم ♪
I didn't mean to hurt you just now.
لم أقصد أن أؤذيك الآن.
♪ I thought this life would drift like a solitary sail ♪
♪ اعتقدت أن هذه الحياة سوف تنجرف مثل شراع وحيد ♪
If anyone's to blame,
إذا كان هناك أي شخص مسؤول عن ذلك،
blame yourself for being nosy
لوم نفسك على كونك فضوليًا
and overestimating yourself.
والمبالغة في تقدير نفسك.
♪ Yet I chanced upon you in the smoke-filled alleyway ♪
♪ ومع ذلك صادفتك في الزقاق المليء بالدخان ♪
♪ Like a fleeting flower falling into ♪
♪ مثل زهرة عابرة تسقط في ♪
Even when you apologize,
حتى عندما تعتذر،
you're so defiant.
أنت متمرد للغاية.
♪ My eyes ♪
♪ عيني ♪
Apologize?
يعتذر؟
♪ Once I was like a frost-edged sword ♪
♪ ذات مرة كنت مثل سيف ذو حدين من الصقيع ♪
♪ Sweeping across the battlefield in gleaming light ♪
♪ اكتساح ساحة المعركة في ضوء ساطع ♪
You're overthinking it.
أنت تفكر في الأمر أكثر من اللازم.
♪ Never thought who'd lay me to rest ♪
♪ لم أفكر أبدًا من الذي سيدفنني ♪
♪ Once unstoppable and sharp ♪
♪ كان ذات يوم لا يمكن إيقافه وكان حادًا ♪
♪ Now my heart's tied to you ♪
♪ الآن قلبي مرتبط بك ♪
[Zhengnian Hall]
[قاعة زينغنيان]
How much did you drink?
كم شربت؟
This is a medical clinic,
هذه عيادة طبية
not an inn.
ليس الداخل.
You...
أنت...
Ning Fei.
نينغ فاي.
Ning Fei!
نينغ فاي!
Shunzi.
شونزي.
Fang.
ناب.
Ning Fei.
نينغ فاي.
Maybe
ربما
because of what happened with Xiao Weiran,
بسبب ما حدث مع شياو ويران،
these past two days,
في اليومين الماضيين،
I've been remembering
لقد كنت أتذكر
things from my childhood.
أشياء من طفولتي.
The three of us were orphans,
كنا الثلاثة أيتامًا،
wandering on the streets and relying on each other.
يتجولون في الشوارع ويعتمدون على بعضهم البعض.
Later,
لاحقاً،
we were taken to the death camp.
لقد تم نقلنا إلى معسكر الموت.
I remember
انا اتذكر
being locked in a cell.
محبوس في زنزانة.
With no food or water,
بدون طعام أو ماء،
I was cold and starving,
كنت أشعر بالبرد والجوع
utterly desperate.
يائسة تماما.
Weiran and Ning Fei
ويران ونينغ فاي
risked their lives to steal a roasted sweet potato
خاطروا بحياتهم لسرقة بطاطا حلوة مشوية
and secretly brought it to me.
وأحضره لي سراً.
Yixiao,
ييشياو،
I hid it in my clothes,
لقد أخفيته في ملابسي،
so no one found it.
لذلك لم يجده أحد.
It's still warm. Eat it now.
لا يزال دافئًا. تناوله الآن.
Yes, hurry and eat.
نعم، اسرع وتناول الطعام.
-We're not hungry.
-نحن لسنا جائعين.
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
You eat it.
أنت تأكله.
Eat it now.
أكله الآن.
Eat.
يأكل.
Is it good?
هل هو جيد؟
If it's good, eat more.
إذا كان جيدًا، فتناول المزيد.
Without them,
بدونهم،
I wouldn't be alive today.
لن أكون على قيد الحياة اليوم.
So what?
وماذا في ذلك؟
The past is the past.
الماضي هو الماضي.
People's hearts change easily.
قلوب الناس تتغير بسهولة.
Everything
كل شئ
in the world is constantly changing.
في العالم يتغير باستمرار.
People's hearts are even harder to read.
إن قلوب الناس أصعب للقراءة.
Once
مرة واحدة
we were enemies.
كنا أعداء.
And now, we're sitting at the same table.
والآن نحن نجلس على نفس الطاولة.
Can the past
هل يمكن للماضي
really stay in the past?
هل حقا تبقى في الماضي؟
Don't you want revenge?
ألا تريد الانتقام؟
You couldn't do it yourself,
لم تتمكن من فعل ذلك بنفسك،
and you're here to lecture me?
وأنت هنا لتلقي علي محاضرة؟
You'll soon see a good show.
سوف ترى عرضًا جيدًا قريبًا.
Be sure to watch it when it starts.
تأكد من مشاهدته عندما يبدأ.
If you don't dare to face it,
إذا لم تجرؤ على مواجهته،
how can you let it go?
كيف يمكنك أن تتخلى عنه؟
Stop looking.
توقف عن النظر
All of you, get out!
جميعكم، اخرجوا!
Be good and leave.
كن جيدا وارحل.
Shunzi.
شونزي.
How did you know
كيف عرفت
to go to Zhengnian Villa to find Master?
الذهاب إلى فيلا Zhengnian للعثور على المعلم؟
It was Brother Weiran.
وكان الأخ ويران.
He said Master had been taken away by bad people,
وقال إن المعلم قد تم أخذه من قبل أشخاص سيئين،
got injured,
لقد أصيب
and might be recovering at Zhengnian Villa.
وقد يتعافى في فيلا زينجنيان.
When?
متى؟
Right before you left,
قبل رحيلك مباشرة،
Brother Weiran
الأخ ويران
told me that.
قال لي ذلك.
Don't move!
لا تتحرك!
I haven't finished stitching your wound.
لم أنتهي من خياطة جرحك.
You…
أنت…
-Brother Ning Fei.
-الأخ نينغ فاي.
Brother Ning Fei!
الأخ نينغ فيي!
-You may tear your wound open.
-يمكنك أن تمزق جرحك.
You idiot, do you want to die?
أيها الأحمق هل تريد أن تموت؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
Ning Fei is here.
نينغ في هنا.
Why is he here again?
لماذا هو هنا مرة أخرى؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
what does he want this time?
ماذا يريد هذه المرة؟
He's here for Xiao Weiran.
إنه هنا من أجل شياو ويران.
So he's finally figured it out.
لقد توصل أخيرا إلى حل.
He's inside.
إنه في الداخل.
Say what you need to say.
قل ما تحتاج إلى قوله.
Ning Fei?
نينغ فاي؟
Why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟
How are things outside?
كيف هي الأمور في الخارج؟
Say something!
قل شيئا!
Does His Highness
هل صاحب السمو
have a message for me?
هل لديك رسالة لي؟
I haven't seen His Highness.
لم أرى سموه.
Feng Suige sent you?
أرسل لك فنغ Suige؟
I have some questions for you.
لدي بعض الأسئلة لك.
The day Yixiao fell off the cliff,
اليوم الذي سقط فيه ييشياو من على الجرف،
you said someone witnessed it.
قلت أن شخصًا شهد ذلك.
Who was it?
من كان؟
I see.
أرى.
It was all your plan.
لقد كان كل ذلك حسب خطتك.
You told me to pull back the patrols…
لقد طلبت مني سحب الدوريات...
Ning Fei, shut up!
نينغ فاي، اصمت!
I'll kill you!
سأقتلك!
Why?
لماذا؟
Why did you try to kill Yixiao?
لماذا حاولت قتل ييشياو؟
Answer me! Answer me! Answer me!
أجبني! أجبني! أجبني!
Answer me!
يجيبني!
Ning Fei!
نينغ فاي!
Let me ask you,
دعني اسألك
if His Highness ordered Yixiao's death,
إذا أمر سموه بقتل ييشياو،
would you kill her or not?
هل ستقتلها أم لا؟
On one side was Jinxiu's great cause
على جانب واحد كانت قضية جينكسيو العظيمة
and a military order.
وأمر عسكري.
On the other side was someone you saw as family.
وعلى الجانب الآخر كان هناك شخص اعتبرته بمثابة العائلة.
How would you choose?
كيف تختار؟
As a soldier,
كجندي،
I must serve my country.
يجب أن أخدم بلدي.
As a subordinate,
بصفتي مرؤوسًا،
I must serve my master.
يجب علي أن أخدم سيدي.
Ning Fei,
نينغ فاي,
I didn't want you to know all this
لم أكن أريدك أن تعرف كل هذا
because I didn't want you to bear
لأنني لم أردك أن تتحمل
this heart-eating pain.
هذا الألم الذي يأكل القلب.
I failed Yixiao.
لقد فشلت في Yixiao.
I betrayed my principles.
لقد خنت مبادئي.
I deserve to go to hell after I die.
أستحق الذهاب إلى الجحيم بعد أن أموت.
That's my retribution!
هذا هو جزائي!
But you don't know anything.
ولكنك لا تعرف شيئا.
None of this had anything to do with you!
لا علاقة لك بأي شيء من هذا !
Yixiao?
يشياو؟
Weiran was right.
وكان ويران على حق.
As subordinates,
كمرؤوسين،
we should serve our master.
ينبغي علينا أن نخدم سيدنا.
If it were me,
لو كنت انا
maybe I'd be torn too.
ربما سأكون ممزقًا أيضًا.
In that case…
في هذه الحالة…
let's stop making things hard
دعونا نتوقف عن جعل الأمور صعبة
for each other.
لبعضهم البعض.
We were family once.
لقد كنا عائلة ذات يوم.
The three of us grew up together,
لقد نشأنا نحن الثلاثة معًا،
fought side by side,
قاتلوا جنبًا إلى جنب،
and protected each other.
وحماوا بعضهم البعض.
That bond was real.
لقد كانت تلك الرابطة حقيقية.
And that's enough.
وهذا يكفي.
I forgot to tell you something.
لقد نسيت أن أخبرك بشيء.
When we were kids,
عندما كنا أطفالا،
you always gave me the precious sweet potatoes.
لقد أعطيتني دائمًا البطاطا الحلوة الثمينة.
I actually didn't like them at all.
في الواقع لم يعجبني إطلاقا.
I only ate them because
لقد أكلتهم فقط لأنني
I didn't want to hurt your feelings.
لم أرد أن أجرح مشاعرك.
Now it's perfect.
الآن أصبح الأمر مثاليًا.
I'll never have to eat them again.
لن أضطر إلى أكلهم مرة أخرى.
From this day on,
من هذا اليوم فصاعدا،
the Three Heroes of Jinxiu are strangers!
الأبطال الثلاثة من جينكسيو هم غرباء!
Swords will draw blood, and all ties are severed!
السيوف ستسيل الدماء، وكل الروابط ستقطع!
Yixiao.
ييشياو.
No.
لا.
The great cause of Jinxiu
القضية العظيمة لجينكسيو
has nothing to do
ليس له علاقة
with me anymore!
معي بعد الآن!
No matter why Xia Jingshi
لا يهم لماذا شيا جينغشي
wants to kill me,
يريد قتلي
whatever scheme
أيا كان المخطط
he's plotting,
إنه يخطط
I won't let him succeed!
لن أسمح له بالنجاح!
I'll make him pay!
سأجعله يدفع الثمن!
Yixiao, stop!
ييشياو، توقف!
Don't talk nonsense.
لا تتحدث هراء.
What do you mean by cutting all ties?
ماذا تقصد بقطع جميع العلاقات؟
With whom are you cutting ties?
مع من تقطع علاقتك؟
Weiran was wrong.
لقد كان ويران مخطئا.
He knows he was wrong.
لقد علم أنه كان مخطئا.
I apologize to you on his behalf.
أعتذر لك نيابة عنه.
Yixiao, don't say things you don't mean.
ييشياو، لا تقل أشياء لا تقصدها.
Yixiao, stop!
ييشياو، توقف!
His Highness must have forced him.
لا بد أن سموه أجبره.
Weiran always obeys him.
ويران يطيعه دائمًا.
This couldn't have been his choice.
لم يكن هذا خياره.
Stop talking!
توقف عن الكلام!
I understand.
أفهم.
Mistakes have consequences.
إن الأخطاء لها عواقب.
A simple apology
اعتذار بسيط
isn't enough.
ليس كافيا.
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
I'll go stab him
سأذهب لأطعنه
to make it up to you.
لتعويضك.
Do you think I want this?
هل تعتقد أنني أريد هذا؟
I don't want this either.
أنا لا أريد هذا أيضًا.
Forget it, Ning Fei.
انسى الأمر، نينغ فيي.
It's useless.
انها غير مجدية.
We can't go back.
لا يمكننا العودة.
None of us can go back.
لا أحد منا يستطيع العودة.
He's not the Xiao Weiran
إنه ليس شياو ويران
we used to know.
كنا نعرف.
And I'm no longer the Yixiao I was.
وأنا لم أعد ييشياو الذي كنت عليه.
How did we end up like this?
كيف انتهى بنا الأمر هكذا؟
What are we gonna do?
ماذا سنفعل؟
Yixiao,
ييشياو،
we promised each other a future.
لقد وعدنا بعضنا البعض بالمستقبل.
Are you asking me?
هل تسألني؟
I don't know either.
انا أيضا لا اعرف.
Yixiao.
ييشياو.
Ning Fei!
نينغ فاي!
What's wrong with you?
ما مشكلتك؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
I recorded
لقد سجلت
their conversation
محادثتهم
word for word
كلمة بكلمة
without missing anything.
دون أن يفوتك أي شيء.
It basically confirms
إنه يؤكد بشكل أساسي
[Xiao: Ning Fei, I had my reasons.]
[شياو: نينغ فاي، كان لدي أسبابي.]
what Miss Yixiao said earlier.
ما قالته الآنسة ييشياو في وقت سابق.
[Ning: What reasons? We adopted]
[نينغ: ما الأسباب؟ لقد تبنّيناها]
[those kids with Yixiao.]
[هؤلاء الأطفال مع ييشياو.]
After the Battle of Pingling,
بعد معركة بينجلينج،
Xia Jingshi and people from Susha
شيا جينغشي وأشخاص من سوشا
were having a secret meeting in camp.
كان لديهم اجتماع سري في المخيم.
Maybe Miss Yixiao
ربما الآنسة Yixiao
overheard something
سمع شيئا ما
and argued with Xia Jingshi.
وتجادل مع شيا جينغشي.
But what it was exactly—
ولكن ما كان بالضبط
we don't know yet.
نحن لا نعرف بعد.
As for Xiao Weiran,
أما بالنسبة لشياو ويران،
do we keep him locked up?
هل نبقيه محبوسا؟
Yes.
نعم.
Hold him until Xia Jingshi comes for him.
امسكيه حتى يأتي شيا جينغشي إليه.
By the way, Your Highness,
وبالمناسبة، صاحب السمو،
Ning Fei was badly injured
لقد أصيب نينغ فاي بجروح بالغة
when fighting Xun Xiang.
عند قتال شون شيانغ.
He was shaken in prison just now
لقد اهتز في السجن للتو
and fainted.
وأغمي عليه.
Miss Yixiao has already taken him
لقد أخذته الآنسة ييشياو بالفعل
to Young Mistress Ling for treatment.
إلى السيدة الشابة لينغ للعلاج.
How is he now?
كيف حاله الآن؟
From what I saw,
ومن ما رأيته،
his wound is festering.
جرحه يتفاقم.
He seems to be poisoned.
يبدو أنه مسموم.
I wonder if Young Mistress Ling is
أتساءل عما إذا كانت السيدة الشابة لينغ هي
able to save him.
قادر على انقاذه.
I need raw Pinellia and Arisaema.
أحتاج إلى Pinellia و Arisaema الخام.
He…
هو…
How is he now?
كيف حاله الآن؟
That arrow was poisoned.
لقد كان هذا السهم مسموما.
It's been left in for too long.
لقد تم تركه لفترة طويلة جدًا.
I'm afraid the poison
أخشى أن السم
has already reached his heart and lungs.
وقد وصل بالفعل إلى قلبه ورئتيه.
It's not that I'm not skilled enough.
ليس الأمر أنني لست ماهرًا بما فيه الكفاية.
Even if my father were here,
حتى لو كان والدي هنا،
he probably couldn't save him.
ربما لم يتمكن من انقاذه.
Then...
ثم...
how long does he have?
كم من الوقت لديه؟
Two or three days, at most.
يومين أو ثلاثة أيام على الأكثر.
Where are you going at this late hour?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب في هذا الوقت المتأخر؟
Meeting Xia Jingshi now
لقاء شيا جينغشي الآن
is hardly a wise move.
إنها ليست خطوة حكيمة على الإطلاق.
I heard Ning Fei is gravely wounded and dying.
سمعت أن نينغ فاي مصاب بجروح خطيرة ويموت.
I figured you'd storm off in anger
اعتقدت أنك ستنسحب غاضبًا
to confront Xia Jingshi.
لمواجهة Xia Jingshi.
I'm not here for anything else today,
أنا لست هنا لأي شيء آخر اليوم،
just to stop you.
فقط لإيقافك.
Thanks for your concern.
شكرا لاهتمامك.
But I need
ولكنني بحاجة
to face some things myself.
لمواجهة بعض الأمور بنفسي.
Have you thought about
هل فكرت في
what to say when you see him?
ماذا تقول عندما تراه؟
Are you sure you can get him to reveal
هل أنت متأكد من أنك تستطيع أن تجعله يكشف؟
why he wants you dead?
لماذا يريد قتلك؟
Or do you think
أم تعتقد
he'll actually tell you the truth?
هل سيخبرك بالحقيقة فعلا؟
Whether he does or not,
سواء فعل ذلك أم لا،
I want to hear his explanation.
أريد أن أسمع تفسيره.
If it weren't for him,
لو لم يكن هو،
we Three Heroes of Jinxiu
نحن أبطال جينكسيو الثلاثة
wouldn't have ended up like this.
لم يكن الأمر لينتهي بهذا الشكل.
I'll settle
سوف اسوي
that score with him sooner or later.
تلك النتيجة معه عاجلا أم آجلا.
You absolutely should.
ينبغي عليك فعل ذلك بالتأكيد.
But if you're thinking of
ولكن إذا كنت تفكر في
killing him today to vent your anger,
قتله اليوم لتنفيس عن غضبك،
I have to remind you—
يجب أن أذكرك-
the royal villa is guarded
الفيلا الملكية محروسة
by Susha's Imperial Guards.
من قبل الحرس الإمبراطوري لسوشا.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
Even if you're lucky enough to kill him,
حتى لو كنت محظوظا بما فيه الكفاية لقتله،
you'll lose your own life
سوف تفقد حياتك
in the process.
في هذه العملية.
Is it really worth it?
هل يستحق الأمر ذلك حقًا؟
[Heaven Coffin Shop]
[متجر نعش السماء]
I decide whether it's worth it or not.
أنا أقرر ما إذا كان الأمر يستحق ذلك أم لا.
Besides,
بجانب،
we don't just do things
نحن لا نفعل الأشياء فقط
because they are worth it.
لأنهم يستحقون ذلك.
You're right.
أنت على حق.
Some things
بعض الأشياء
are worth
تستحق
going through hell and high water for.
المرور عبر الجحيم والمياه المرتفعة من أجل.
[Heaven Coffin Shop]
[متجر نعش السماء]
But if you were going to act on impulse,
ولكن إذا كنت ستتصرف بناء على الدافع،
you would've done it long ago.
لقد كنت قد فعلت ذلك منذ زمن طويل.
You've swallowed your pride
لقد ابتلعت كبريائك
and endured until now.
وصمدت حتى الآن.
Wasn't it all to uncover the truth?
ألم يكن كل هذا من أجل اكتشاف الحقيقة؟
[Heaven Coffin Shop]
[متجر نعش السماء]
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
I personally went to Zhengnian Hall.
لقد ذهبت شخصيا إلى قاعة Zhengnian.
Officer Ning is
الضابط نينغ هو
indeed badly wounded.
مصاب بجروح بالغة بالفعل.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
should we
هل ينبغي علينا
bring him back?
اعادته؟
[Xia Jingshi]
[شيا جينغشي]
When did the three of them meet?
متى التقى الثلاثة؟
According to the patrol unit,
وبحسب وحدة الدوريات،
it was around noon yesterday.
لقد كان حوالي الظهر أمس.
[Xia Jingshi]
[شيا جينغشي]
Military Advisor Xiao was locked up
تم حبس المستشار العسكري شياو
by Feng Suige
بواسطة فنغ سويج
in the patrol unit's prison.
في سجن وحدة الدوريات.
[Seal of Xia Jingshi, Prince of Zhennan]
[ختم شيا جينغشي، أمير جينان]
It's surrounded by guards.
إنها محاطة بالحراس.
Our men can't get in.
رجالنا لا يستطيعون الدخول.
Has Yixiao been there?
هل كان ييشياو هناك؟
No.
لا.
Take this letter
خذ هذه الرسالة
to Xue Yan.
إلى شيويه يان.
Tell him
أخبره
to get Xiao Weiran out
لإخراج شياو ويران
at all costs.
بأي ثمن.
If needed,
إذا لزم الأمر،
he can use the marriage alliance as leverage.
بإمكانه استخدام تحالف الزواج كوسيلة ضغط.
Yes.
نعم.
Xia Jingshi only sent someone
أرسل Xia Jingshi شخصًا ما فقط
to Zhengnian Hall
إلى قاعة Zhengnian
to ask about Ning Fei.
للاستفسار عن نينغ في.
Other than that,
بخلاف ذلك،
he hasn't done anything else.
ولم يفعل أي شيء آخر.
Who would've thought the Prince of Zhennan
من كان يظن أن أمير جينان
would be so heartless?
هل سيكون بلا قلب إلى هذه الدرجة؟
Ning Fei has been
لقد كان نينغ في
through thick and thin with him.
في السراء والضراء معه.
Now that Ning Fei is dying,
الآن وقد مات نينغ فاي،
he just turns his back on him.
إنه فقط يدير ظهره له.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
doesn't he fear
ألا يخاف؟
disheartening his men?
تثبيط عزيمة رجاله؟
I had you leak Ning Fei's condition
لقد سربت لك حالة نينغ فاي
to Xia Jingshi
لشيا جينغشي
not to see how cold he is
لا أرى مدى برودته
to his subordinates.
إلى مرؤوسيه.
Then what's your intention?
إذن ما هي نيتك؟
If a Jinxiu guard officer
إذا كان ضابط حرس جينكسيو
dies in Susha right before the wedding,
يموت في سوشا قبل الزفاف مباشرة،
regardless of the reason,
بغض النظر عن السبب،
it could sabotage
قد يؤدي ذلك إلى التخريب
the marriage alliance.
تحالف الزواج.
Xia Jingshi
شيا جينغشي
hasn't made a fuss
لم يثير ضجة
about Ning Fei,
نبذة عن نينغ فاي،
which means he doesn't want the alliance ruined either.
وهذا يعني أنه لا يريد تدمير التحالف أيضًا.
So Your Highness thinks
لذا يعتقد سموكم
this marriage alliance is part of his plan?
هل هذا الزواج جزء من خطته؟
No.
لا.
It wasn't Xia Jingshi
لم يكن شيا جينغشي
who proposed it.
من اقترح ذلك؟
It was the Emperor of Jinxiu—Xia Jingyan.
لقد كان إمبراطور جينكسيو - شيا جينغيان.
At most, Xia Jingshi is using
على الأكثر، شيا جينغشي يستخدم
the marriage for his own ends.
الزواج من أجل غاياته الخاصة.
Then what exactly does he want?
إذن ماذا يريد بالضبط؟
Fu Yixiao.
فو ييشياو.
That's why Xia Jingshi came
لهذا السبب جاء شيا جينغشي
for this alliance—
لهذا التحالف—
to take Fu Yixiao away.
ليأخذ فو Yixiao بعيدًا.
Sister,
أخت،
stop wiping.
توقف عن المسح.
You haven't slept all night.
لم تنم طوال الليل.
Go get some rest.
اذهب للحصول على بعض الراحة.
How is he?
كيف حاله؟
I just finished the acupuncture.
لقد انتهيت للتو من الوخز بالإبر.
Some of the poisoned blood has been drained.
لقد تم تصريف بعض الدماء المسمومة .
Will he wake up?
هل سيستيقظ؟
It's already a miracle that he made it through the night.
إنها معجزة بالفعل أنه تمكن من اجتياز الليل.
There were several times
كانت هناك عدة مرات
I couldn't even find his pulse.
ولم أستطع حتى العثور على نبضه.
Sister,
أخت،
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
It's all my fault.
إنه خطئي كله.
My medical skills aren't good enough.
مهاراتي الطبية ليست جيدة بما فيه الكفاية.
Don't say that.
لا تقل ذلك.
You've done your best.
لقد بذلت قصارى جهدك.
It's my fault.
إنه خطئي.
I shouldn't have doubted him.
لا ينبغي لي أن أشك فيه.
I should've seen from the start
كان ينبغي لي أن أرى من البداية
that this had nothing to do with him.
أن هذا ليس له علاقة به.
I never should've dragged him into this.
لا ينبغي لي أن أدخله في هذا الأمر أبدًا.
And I definitely shouldn't have said those harsh words.
وبالتأكيد لم يكن ينبغي لي أن أقول هذه الكلمات القاسية.
Those who want me dead are Xiao Weiran
أولئك الذين يريدون قتلي هم شياو ويران
and Xia Jingshi.
وشيا جينغشي.
He's never done
لم ينتهي أبدا
anything wrong.
أي شيء خاطئ.
When he was little, he used to say
عندما كان صغيرا كان يقول
he wanted a home.
لقد أراد منزلًا.
He said we Three Heroes of Jinxiu
وقال نحن أبطال جينكسيو الثلاثة
should go somewhere
ينبغي أن تذهب إلى مكان ما
with mountains and rivers
مع الجبال والأنهار
and have a house to grow old in together.
ويكون لدينا منزل لنعيش فيه معًا.
We'll bask in the sun,
سوف نستمتع بأشعة الشمس
grow some flowers,
زراعة بعض الزهور،
and stop fighting and killing.
والتوقف عن القتال والقتل.
The house doesn't need to be big—
لا يحتاج المنزل إلى أن يكون كبيرًا
just a place we can call home.
مجرد مكان يمكننا أن نسميه موطنا.
I don't know what else I can do
لا أعرف ماذا يمكنني أن أفعل غير ذلك
for him now.
له الآن.
With this,
مع هذا،
at least he can finally have a home.
على الأقل يمكنه أن يحصل على منزل أخيرًا.
[Zhengnian Hall]
[قاعة زينغنيان]
Sir.
سيد.
We're here.
نحن هنا.
[Ling Feng, Master of Zhengnian Villa]
[لينغ فنغ، سيد فيلا زينغنيان]
[Zhengnian Hall]
[قاعة زينغنيان]
You fool.
يا أحمق.
Wake up, Ning Fei.
استيقظ، نينغ فاي.
Ning Fei!
نينغ فاي!
Ling Xueying!
لينغ شيويينغ!
Father!
أب!
Let go of him.
اتركه يذهب
Your hands…
يديك…
Let go.
اتركه.
Let go of him!
اتركه!
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I'm treating him.
انا اعالجه
Who taught you to treat a patient
من علمك علاج المريض؟
while bawling your eyes out like that?
بينما تبكي عينيك هكذا؟
You.
أنت.
Me?
أنا؟
Give me a break!
أعطني استراحة!
Father, save him.
يا أبتاه أنقذه.
Please help him.
من فضلك ساعده.
That coffin by the door
هذا التابوت بجانب الباب
is prepared for him?
هل تم إعداده له؟
Well-timed.
في الوقت المناسب.
We'll be needing it soon.
سوف نحتاجه قريبا.
Father,
أب،
please save him.
من فضلك انقذه.
I'm begging you to save him.
أنا أتوسل إليك لإنقاذه.
Father.
أب.
Save him?
انقذه؟
He's already at death's door.
لقد وصل بالفعل إلى باب الموت.
Do you want me to ruin my spotless record?
هل تريد مني أن أدمر سجلي النظيف؟
Come with me.
تعال معي.
Father,
أب،
what are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Got any silver on you?
هل لديك أي فضة عليك؟
Pay the coachman for me.
ادفع للسائق من أجلي.
My medicine box
صندوق أدويتي
is still being held as collateral.
لا يزال يتم الاحتفاظ به كضمان.
Listen to me.
استمع لي.
The box is more important than him.
الصندوق أهم منه.
Hurry, let's go.
اسرع دعنا نذهب
Father,
أب،
what are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
You paid the coachman for me?
هل دفعت للسائق من أجلي؟
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو.
Lord Ling.
اللورد لينغ.
I've had people searching for you all over.
لقد كان هناك أشخاص يبحثون عنك في كل مكان.
Why has it been
لماذا كان ذلك؟
so hard to find you?
من الصعب جدًا العثور عليك؟
A patient asked me to find some medicine for him.
طلب مني أحد المرضى أن أجد له بعض الأدوية.
What do you need me for?
لماذا تحتاجني؟
Naturally, I need your help.
بطبيعة الحال، أنا بحاجة إلى مساعدتك.
I need you to check on a friend's injury.
أريد منك التحقق من إصابة صديق.
What kind of friend
أي نوع من الأصدقاء
deserves such concern from Your Highness?
هل يستحق هذا الاهتمام من سموكم؟
She's inside.
إنها في الداخل.
Come with me.
تعال معي.
Father.
أب.
Come.
يأتي.
Clench your fist.
أحكم قبضة يدك.
Harder.
أصعب.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Let me take a look.
دعني ألقي نظرة.
Aside from the injury to your hand,
بصرف النظر عن الإصابة التي لحقت بيدك،
you also have amnesia.
أنت تعاني من فقدان الذاكرة أيضاً.
Falling from that height
السقوط من هذا الارتفاع
and not ending up in pieces,
ولا تنتهي إلى قطع،
you must've been caught
لا بد وأنك قد تم القبض عليك
by branches on the way down.
من خلال الفروع في الطريق إلى الأسفل.
They slowed your fall.
لقد أبطأوا سقوطك.
As for the amnesia,
أما بالنسبة لفقدان الذاكرة،
since it's from a head trauma,
لأنه ناتج عن صدمة في الرأس،
it means there's a clot in your brain.
وهذا يعني أن هناك جلطة في دماغك.
The clot
الجلطة
is the real problem.
هذه هي المشكلة الحقيقية.
Torn tendons can be reattached.
يمكن إعادة ربط الأوتار الممزقة.
As for the clot,
أما بالنسبة للجلطة،
with time and treatment,
مع الوقت والعلاج،
it can be fixed.
يمكن اصلاحه.
Yixiao,
ييشياو،
I told you
أخبرتك
my father would definitely heal you.
والدي سوف يشفيك بالتأكيد.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
I have a difficult request.
لدي طلب صعب.
My injury is not
إصابتي ليست
worth troubling you, Lord Ling.
يستحق أن يزعجك، يا سيد لينج.
I only hope you can
أتمنى فقط أن تتمكن من ذلك
save my brother.
أنقذ أخي.
Brother?
أخ؟
That dying man on the bed?
هذا الرجل المحتضر على السرير؟
Yes.
نعم.
Haven't you already prepared
ألم تقم بالتحضير بالفعل
a coffin for him?
نعش له؟
Better to bury him soon.
من الأفضل دفنه قريبًا.
Father,
أب،
are you seriously going
هل انت ذاهب بجدية؟
to just let him die?
هل نتركه يموت فقط؟
I seriously am.
أنا جديا.
His pulse is shallow, fading fast,
نبضه ضحل، يتلاشى بسرعة،
barely there— just the signs of heart failure.
بالكاد هناك - فقط علامات قصور القلب.
It won't be long
لن يمضي وقت طويل
before he takes his last breath.
قبل أن يأخذ أنفاسه الأخيرة.
I, Ling Feng, only treat
أنا، لينغ فينغ، أعالج فقط
those who can be saved.
الذين يمكن إنقاذهم.
I never fight Hades for a soul.
أنا لا أقاتل هاديس من أجل روح أبدًا.
Lord Ling.
اللورد لينغ.
Please, save him!
من فضلك انقذه!
Yixiao, don't do this.
ييشياو، لا تفعل هذا.
Father,
أب،
Yixiao is my sister.
ييشياو هي أختي.
Her brother
شقيقها
is my brother.
هو أخي.
Lord Ling, your skills are unmatched.
يا سيد لينج، مهاراتك لا مثيل لها.
There must be another way.
لا بد أن يكون هناك طريقة أخرى.
If you can save him,
إذا كنت تستطيع انقاذه،
I'll do anything you ask.
سأفعل أي شيء تطلبه.
Miss,
يفتقد،
rules are rules.
القواعد هي القواعد.
No amount of pleading will change that.
لن يغير ذلك أي قدر من التوسل.
Get up.
استيقظ.
I won't.
أنا لن.
Lord Ling,
اللورد لينغ،
your skills
مهاراتك
can work miracles,
يمكن أن تصنع المعجزات،
and you have a kind heart.
ولديك قلب طيب.
Please, I beg you.
من فضلك، أتوسل إليك.
You can't just leave him to die.
لا يمكنك تركه ليموت.
Yixiao.
ييشياو.
I can!
أنا استطيع!
Lord Ling!
اللورد لينغ!
Yixiao.
ييشياو.
Father!
أب!
Wait for me, Father.
انتظرني يا أبي.
She's my sister.
إنها أختي.
You must help her.
يجب عليك مساعدتها.
Zhengnian Hall.
قاعة زينغنيان.
I-I'm in Yujing now.
أنا في يوجينج الآن.
I need a place to stay, don't I?
أحتاج إلى مكان للإقامة، أليس كذلك؟
Besides,
بجانب،
Zhengnian Villa
فيلا زنجنيان
having a branch in Yujing
لديه فرع في يوجينج
isn't a bad thing, right?
ليس شيئًا سيئًا، أليس كذلك؟
Such a big house
مثل هذا البيت الكبير
must be expensive.
يجب أن تكون باهظة الثمن.
Where did you get the money?
من أين حصلت على المال؟
I put it on the Emperor of Susha's tab.
وضعته على علامة تبويب إمبراطور سوشا.
You foolish girl!
يا فتاة حمقاء!
You've got some nerve!
لقد حصلت على بعض الشجاعة!
You're driving me crazy.
أنت تقودني إلى الجنون.
Father, where are you going?
أبي إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
Where am I going?
إلى أين أنا ذاهب؟
You're such a troublemaker!
أنت مثير للمشاكل!
I have to run.
لا بد لي من الركض.
With all that debt you racked up,
مع كل تلك الديون التي تراكمت عليك،
how am I supposed to pay it back?
كيف من المفترض أن أسددها؟
Also,
أيضًا،
that guy is practically in his grave already,
هذا الرجل في قبره بالفعل
and you want me to save him?
وتريدني أن أنقذه؟
Why don't you just bury me
لماذا لا تدفنني فقط؟
with him and be done with it?
معه وانتهي من الأمر؟
Father!
أب!
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
Lord Ling,
اللورد لينغ،
forgive me.
سامحني.
Your Highness, what's the meaning of this?
صاحب السمو ما معنى هذا؟
That girl even knelt to you.
حتى أن تلك الفتاة ركعت لك.
Helping her
مساعدتها
would hardly cost you a thing.
لن يكلفك ذلك أي شيء تقريبًا.
She knelt to me. So what?
ركعت أمامي. وماذا في ذلك؟
I could kneel to her too if needed.
أستطيع أن أركع لها أيضًا إذا لزم الأمر.
Besides,
بجانب،
am I supposed to help everyone who asks?
هل من المفترض أن أساعد كل من يطلب ذلك؟
Those stupid rules of your Zhengnian Villa
تلك القواعد الغبية لفيلتك زينجنيان
should be changed.
ينبغي أن يتغير.
Take Lord Ling to the medical hall.
خذ اللورد لينج إلى القاعة الطبية.
Lord Ling,
اللورد لينغ،
please.
لو سمحت.
Trying to strong-arm me, huh?
تحاول أن تجبرني، أليس كذلك؟
Wanna fight?
هل تريد القتال؟
Don't make me prick you with needles!
لا تجعلني أوخزك بالإبر!
-Father! -Let go of me!
-أبي! -اتركني!
I'm warning you, I'll prick you with needles!
أنا أحذرك، سأوخزك بالإبر!
Let go!
اتركه!
This is my father's
هذا هو والدي
Seven-Aperture Acupuncture.
الوخز بالإبر ذو السبعة فتحات.
It can bring the dead back to life.
يمكنه إعادة الموتى إلى الحياة.
It looks simple,
يبدو بسيطا،
but every twist
ولكن كل منعطف
and insertion
والإدراج
requires precise skill.
يتطلب مهارة دقيقة.
Since my father
منذ والدي
agreed to save Ning Fei,
وافق على إنقاذ نينغ في،
he's definitely not going to die.
إنه لن يموت بالتأكيد.
Didn't Lord Ling just say
ألم يقل اللورد لينغ للتو
this man couldn't be saved?
هذا الرجل لا يمكن انقاذه؟
Did I say he'd survive?
هل قلت أنه سيبقى على قيد الحياة؟
I've only temporarily sealed
لقد قمت بإغلاقه مؤقتا فقط
his heart meridian
خط طول قلبه
to control the poison in his blood.
للسيطرة على السم في دمه.
To put it plainly,
ولكي نكون واضحين،
I'm just buying him two more days.
سأشتريه له يومين آخرين فقط.
That's impossible.
هذا مستحيل.
Nothing is impossible.
لا شيء مستحيل .
I don't do miracles.
أنا لا أصنع المعجزات.
When I say he can't be saved,
عندما أقول أنه لا يمكن إنقاذه،
he can't be saved.
لا يمكن انقاذه.
Would I lie about that?
هل أكذب بشأن ذلك؟
If he can't be saved,
إذا لم يكن من الممكن إنقاذه،
why make him live two more days?
لماذا نجعله يعيش يومين إضافيين؟
Just because I can't
فقط لأنني لا أستطيع
save him doesn't mean no one…
انقاذه لا يعني لا أحد
can save him.
يمكن انقاذه.
Who can save him?
من يستطيع انقاذه؟
There is a place where they have
هناك مكان حيث لديهم
a secret blood replacement technique.
تقنية سرية لاستبدال الدم.
It might save his life.
ربما ينقذ حياته.
Where is that place?
أين هذا المكان؟
It's located outside the borders
إنه يقع خارج الحدود
of Susha and Jinxiu.
سوشا وجينكسيو.
Ordinary people can't even
الناس العاديون لا يستطيعون حتى
hear of this secret place,
اسمع عن هذا المكان السري،
let alone get in.
ناهيك عن الدخول.
They have a rule—
لديهم قاعدة—
anyone who enters
أي شخص يدخل
must become one of them
يجب أن تصبح واحدا منهم
and swear a blood oath
وأقسم يمين الدم
to never betray them or escape.
لكي لا نخونهم أو نهرب منهم أبدًا.
Father,
أب،
how do you know about this place?
كيف تعرف عن هذا المكان؟
I once saved one of those people
لقد أنقذت ذات مرة أحد هؤلاء الأشخاص
in the woods.
في الغابة.
That's how I knew their secret.
هكذا عرفت سرهم.
Miss,
يفتقد،
are you sure about this?
هل أنت متأكد من هذا؟
If you send your brother there,
إذا أرسلت أخاك إلى هناك،
even if he's saved,
حتى لو تم إنقاذه،
he'll likely never be free again.
من المرجح أنه لن يكون حرا مرة أخرى.
I'm sure.
انا متأكد.
Being alive is more important than anything.
إن البقاء على قيد الحياة هو أكثر أهمية من أي شيء.
I agree.
أنا موافق.
I agree to any condition.
أوافق على أي شرط.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Does he have any blood relatives?
هل لديه أي أقارب بالدم؟
The contract
العقد
requires a handprint from a close relative.
يتطلب بصمة يد من أحد الأقارب المقربين.
He's an orphan.
إنه يتيم.
I'm the only family he has.
أنا العائلة الوحيدة التي لديه.
That's a problem.
هذه مشكلة.
What's the problem?
ما هي المشكلة؟
It's just a handprint.
إنها مجرد بصمة يد.
I'll do it.
سأفعل ذلك.
If you put your handprint,
إذا وضعت بصمة يدك،
you'll be
سوف تكون
the guarantor.
الضامن.
Their rules are strict.
قواعدهم صارمة.
What they say goes.
ما يقولونه هو الصحيح.
If your brother escapes,
إذا هرب أخوك،
you'll need to bring him back.
سوف تحتاج إلى إعادته.
If you can't,
إذا لم تتمكن من ذلك،
you'll have to repay
سوف تضطر إلى السداد
the debt of gratitude in his place.
دين الامتنان في مكانه.
I understand.
أفهم.
Who's going to draft the contract?
من الذي سيقوم بصياغة العقد؟
You don't understand.
أنت لا تفهم.
They are going to save his life.
إنهم سوف ينقذون حياته.
If he runs,
إذا ركض،
you'll have to give your life in his place.
سيتعين عليك أن تضحي بحياتك في مكانه.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
I'm willing to bear all consequences.
أنا مستعد لتحمل كافة العواقب.
Father,
أب،
what kind of place is that?
ما هذا النوع من المكان؟
Why does it have
لماذا لديه
even more rules than our Zhengnian Villa?
هل هناك قواعد أكثر من فيلا Zhengnian الخاصة بنا؟
What do you know?
ماذا تعرف؟
If people there are willing to help,
إذا كان هناك أشخاص على استعداد للمساعدة،
except for those already claimed by death,
باستثناء تلك التي أودت بحياتها بالفعل،
they can save anyone.
بإمكانهم انقاذ أي شخص.
Father,
أب،
that doesn't sound like you.
هذا لا يبدو مثلك.
In all my life,
في كل حياتي،
I've never seen you admit someone else is better.
لم أرى قط أنك تعترف بأن شخصًا آخر أفضل منك.
Then you haven't seen enough.
إذن أنت لم ترى ما يكفي.
Draft the contract now.
قم بصياغة العقد الآن.
I'm afraid Ning Fei won't last much longer.
أخشى أن نينغ فاي لن يستمر لفترة أطول.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Making Xia Jingshi and the others
صنع شيا جينغشي والآخرين
believe that Ning Fei is already dead.
أعتقد أن نينغ فاي قد مات بالفعل.
It makes things easier.
إنه يجعل الأمور أسهل.
Once he leaves this place,
بمجرد أن يغادر هذا المكان،
he'll no longer be involved in worldly conflicts.
لن يشارك بعد الآن في الصراعات الدنيوية.
Jinxiu and Susha
جينكسيو وسوشا
will have nothing to do with him anymore.
لن يكون له أي علاقة به بعد الآن.
This is probably
ربما هذا هو
the best ending for him.
أفضل نهاية له.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Miss,
يفتقد،
I've taken the contract.
لقد أخذت العقد.
From this day on,
من هذا اليوم فصاعدا،
you'll be held accountable
سوف تكون مسؤولا
for everything
لكل شيء
this man does.
هذا الرجل يفعل ذلك.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
We're not related by blood,
نحن لسنا مرتبطين بالدم
but we'll be family for life.
لكننا سنكون عائلة مدى الحياة.
As long as he's alive, that's enough.
ما دام على قيد الحياة، فهذا يكفي.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
I'll draw you a map in a bit
سأرسم لك خريطة بعد قليل
and show you the location.
وأظهر لك الموقع.
Once your people
بمجرد أن يصبح شعبك
send him there,
أرسله هناك
they'll take him
سوف يأخذونه
after they see the letter.
بعد أن رأوا الرسالة.
Remember—
يتذكر-
when your people arrive,
عندما يصل شعبك،
they must be blindfolded
يجب أن يكونوا معصوبي الأعين
and ask no questions at any time.
ولا تسأل أي أسئلة في أي وقت.
Understood.
مفهومة.
[Jingming Garden]
[حديقة جينغمينغ]
Thank you for coming in person,
شكرا لك على حضورك شخصيا،
Minister Shen.
الوزير شين.
I've brought the man.
لقد أحضرت الرجل.
[Jingming Garden]
[حديقة جينغمينغ]
On behalf of His Highness,
بالنيابة عن صاحب السمو،
I thank you.
أشكرك.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Aren't you curious
ألا تشعر بالفضول؟
why Feng Suige let you return?
لماذا سمح لك فينج سويجي بالعودة؟
Susha had promised
لقد وعدت سوشا
to return Yixiao to me.
لإعادة Yixiao لي.
But I gave that spot to you.
ولكنني أعطيتك هذا المكان.
You shouldn't have saved me.
لا ينبغي لك أن تنقذني.
I shouldn't have saved you?
ألا ينبغي لي أن أنقذك؟
If I hadn't saved you,
لو لم أنقذك،
should I have just let you die?
هل كان يجب علي أن أتركك تموت؟
Better I kill you myself
من الأفضل أن أقتلك بنفسي
than let Feng Suige do it!
ثم دع فينج سويجي يفعل ذلك!
What did you do wrong?
ماذا فعلت خطأ؟
I failed to kill Yixiao.
لقد فشلت في قتل ييشياو.
Do you have a death wish?
هل لديك رغبة في الموت؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
Yixiao cannot be spared.
لا يمكن الاستغناء عن ييشياو.
She's forgotten everything.
لقد نسيت كل شيء.
She was about
كانت على وشك
to come back to me.
لتعود إليّ.
Why did you act on your own?
لماذا تصرفت بمفردك؟
Why did you ruin everything?
لماذا دمرت كل شيء؟
She already knows
إنها تعرف بالفعل
you were the one who shot her off the cliff.
لقد كنت أنت الشخص الذي أطلق عليها النار من فوق المنحدر.
She also knows
وهي تعرف أيضا
I sent assassins after her.
لقد أرسلت قتلة وراءها.
You know better than anyone
أنت تعرف أفضل من أي شخص آخر
how capable Yixiao is.
ما مدى قدرة ييشياو.
If she lives,
إذا عاشت،
she'll be a threat to you.
إنها ستكون تهديدًا لك.
You're in no position
أنت لست في وضع جيد
to make decisions for me.
لاتخاذ القرارات نيابة عني.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
I just couldn't bear
لم أستطع أن أتحمل
to see you backed into a corner again.
أن أراك محاصرًا في الزاوية مرة أخرى.
Everything I've done
كل ما فعلته
was all for you!
كان كل شيء من أجلك!
You resent me.
أنت تستاء مني.
I don't dare.
لا أجرؤ.
You resent me for going back on my word.
أنت تستاء مني لأنني تراجعت عن كلمتي.
You resent me for failing to protect Yixiao.
أنت تستاء مني لفشلي في حماية ييشياو.
Yixiao is your family.
ييشياو هي عائلتك.
How could you bring yourself to kill her?
كيف يمكنك أن تجبر نفسك على قتلها؟
It's all my fault
إنه خطئي كله
that you ended up like this.
أنك انتهيت مثل هذا.
No!
لا!
When we chose to follow you,
عندما اخترنا أن نتبعك،
we swore an oath.
لقد أقسمنا اليمين.
Our lives
حياتنا
belong to you.
تنتمي إليك.
Leave now.
إرحل الآن.
You've been exposed.
لقد تم الكشف عنك.
Feng Suige will definitely have people
فينج سويجي سيكون لديه أشخاص بالتأكيد
watching you.
أراقبك.
Go to the border now
اذهب إلى الحدود الآن
and gather men.
وجمع الرجال.
Once I find a way to escape,
بمجرد أن أجد طريقة للهروب،
you'll be there waiting.
سوف تكون هناك في انتظار.
Yes.
نعم.
[In Memory of Late Mother Qingyu]
[في ذكرى الأم الراحلة تشينغيو]
Where exactly are you
أين أنت بالضبط؟
sending Ning Fei?
إرسال نينغ فاي؟
Don't ask too much.
لا تطلب الكثير .
When it's time for you to know,
عندما يحين الوقت لتعرف،
you'll know.
سوف تعرف.
[In Memory of Late Mother Qingyu]
[في ذكرى الأم الراحلة تشينغيو]
Does it have something to do
هل له علاقة بشيء ما؟
with my mother?
مع والدتي؟
I said don't ask.
قلت لا تسأل.
What's that girl to you?
ما هذه الفتاة بالنسبة لك؟
She's Fu Yixiao, the Red-Clad General of Jinxiu,
إنها فو يشياو، جنرال جينكسيو ذو الملابس الحمراء،
who nearly killed me
الذي كاد أن يقتلني
with an arrow at the Battle of Pingling.
بسهم في معركة بينجلينج.
An enemy?
عدو؟
She used to be.
لقد كانت كذلك.
And now?
و الآن؟